<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.sergiopesch.voco</id>
  <name>VOCO</name>
  <summary>A voice-native interface layer designed for speed and precision</summary>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <developer id="com.sergiopesch">
    <name>Sergio Pesch</name>
  </developer>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">VOCO.desktop</launchable>
  <description>
    <p>VOCO is a Linux desktop dictation tool for people who want fast, private voice capture with local transcription by default.</p>
    <p>It stays in the tray, listens on demand, and keeps visible state compact. Its optional realtime conversation mode sends microphone audio to OpenAI only after the user explicitly starts that mode.</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Tray-first workflow with a compact command panel</li>
      <li>Onboarding for microphone setup and hotkeys</li>
      <li>GitHub Release update checks for manual install channels</li>
      <li>Clear Linux-specific install, upgrade, and troubleshooting guidance</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/sergiopesch/voco</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/sergiopesch/voco/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/sergiopesch/voco</url>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <releases>
    <release version="2026.0.21" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Adds persistent VOCO Dictation input-source support with revisable live preedit, authoritative local checkpoints, exact-prefix delivery, and recoverable fail-closed final transcripts.</p>
        <p>Unifies tray and settings state, adds safe configuration recovery and single-instance ownership, and hardens model-cache integrity, installers, private IPC, and release verification.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2026.0.17" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <p>Adds bounded 10-minute dictation, chunked local transcription, append-only live cursor previews, and safer final transcript reconciliation.</p>
        <p>Improves audio capture throughput and memory use, adds optional local model and realtime assistant paths, and hardens Linux packaging and release verification.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
